<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Codejago</title>
        <link>http://codejago.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Codejago</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <atom:link href="http://codejago.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Jumping through Hoops - Installing the Java SDK</title>
            <link>http://codejago.com/posts/1/01/jumping-through-hoops-installing-the-java-sdk/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://codejago.com/posts/1/01/jumping-through-hoops-installing-the-java-sdk/</guid>
            <description>Installing the Java SDK &amp;hellip; yet again &amp;hellip; for the eleventy billionth time Always looking out for that quick and easy way to install the Java SDK. This time, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try sdkman which is a tool for managing multiple versions of the Java SDK. It&amp;rsquo;s a little more than that, but that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m going to use it for.
I&amp;rsquo;m using Debian 10, so I&amp;rsquo;ll follow the instructions for Linux.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="installing-the-java-sdk--yet-again--for-the-eleventy-billionth-time">Installing the Java SDK &hellip; yet again &hellip; for the eleventy billionth time</h2>
<p>Always looking out for that quick and easy way to install the Java SDK. This time, I&rsquo;m going to try <a href="https://sdkman.io/">sdkman</a> which is a
tool for managing multiple versions of the Java SDK. It&rsquo;s a little more than that, but that&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;m going to use it for.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m using Debian 10, so I&rsquo;ll follow the instructions for <a href="https://sdkman.io/install">Linux</a>.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>$ curl -s <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;https://get.sdkman.io&#34;</span> | bash
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>I still had to open <a href="https://jdk.java.net/20/">https://jdk.java.net/20/</a> to find the latest version number. I&rsquo;m sure there&rsquo;s a way to do that programmatically.</p>
<p>Then, open a new terminal window and run the following:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>$ sdk install java 20.0.2-open
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>...
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>Setting java 20.0.2-open as default.
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>One thing it did do was set the package to be the default&hellip; without asking&hellip; Anyway, turns out <code>sdk default java 20.0.2-open</code> will set it to the stated version.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>One Dumbass Tool to Rule Them All</title>
            <link>http://codejago.com/posts/1/01/one-dumbass-tool-to-rule-them-all/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://codejago.com/posts/1/01/one-dumbass-tool-to-rule-them-all/</guid>
            <description>Plato: Greetings, Homer, wise in the ways of technology! I, Plato, am a fervent advocate of wielding a diverse set of tools in the pursuit of crafting digital wonders.
Homer: Hey there, Plato! I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this one tool for as long as I can remember. It&amp;rsquo;s like my trusty ol&amp;rsquo; donut – reliable and delicious.
Plato: Ah, Homer, your analogy is as delightful as a philosopher&amp;rsquo;s discourse at the agora.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Plato:</strong> Greetings, Homer, wise in the ways of technology! I, Plato, am a fervent advocate of wielding a diverse set of tools in the pursuit of crafting digital wonders.</p>
<p><strong>Homer:</strong> Hey there, Plato! I&rsquo;ve been using this one tool for as long as I can remember. It&rsquo;s like my trusty ol&rsquo; donut – reliable and delicious.</p>

    <img src="/images/hammer-nail.png"  alt="Everything looks like a hammer to a nail"  class="left"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p><strong>Plato:</strong> Ah, Homer, your analogy is as delightful as a philosopher&rsquo;s discourse at the agora. But consider this: just as a philosopher seeks knowledge from various sources, a developer should draw from an array of tools to tackle the intricacies of the digital realm.</p>
<p><strong>Homer:</strong> Listen, buddy, I get what you&rsquo;re saying, but let me put it this way: when I have my trusty hammer, everything starts looking like a nail. I know my tool inside-out, and it does the job every time, without any fancy acrobatics.</p>
<p><strong>Plato:</strong> A valid point, Homer, akin to Socrates&rsquo; commitment to his method of dialectics. Yet, imagine constructing a grand digital edifice with just a single tool. It&rsquo;s like building the Parthenon with only a chisel – effective for some parts, but inadequate for others.</p>
<p><strong>Homer:</strong> You know, Plato, sometimes I think too many tools are like having too many toppings on a pizza – it just gets confusing. With my one tool, I don&rsquo;t need to worry about compatibility or juggling a bunch of different things.</p>
<p><strong>Plato:</strong> An intriguing perspective, Homer, reminiscent of Diogenes living a minimalist life in his barrel. However, consider a scenario where your trusty tool can&rsquo;t solve a particular challenge. A diverse toolkit would be like a treasure chest of solutions, each key unlocking a unique door.</p>
<p><strong>Plato picks up an example of using multiple tools</strong></p>
<p><strong>Plato:</strong> Imagine, Homer, you&rsquo;re building a web application. Your trusty hammer, your single tool, excels at certain frontend tasks. But what if you encounter a complex backend integration challenge? Here, a backend framework could be your chisel, chipping away the intricacies of data handling.</p>
<p><strong>Homer counters with a Homer-esque example</strong></p>
<p><strong>Homer:</strong> Okay, okay, Plato. Let me counter your example. You&rsquo;re a developer working on a mobile app, right? Well, I say you stick to your fancy tools and frameworks, but when it comes to designing that perfect user interface, you can&rsquo;t go wrong with my tried-and-true donut analogy. A single tool, much like a single flavor, can create a masterpiece that everyone craves.</p>
<p><strong>Plato:</strong> Ah, Homer, you do have a knack for making your point in the most unconventional way. But remember, just as a poet employs a rich vocabulary to convey depth and emotion, a developer&rsquo;s toolkit paints a canvas of possibilities. Each tool a brushstroke, together creating a digital symphony.</p>
<p><strong>Plato contemplates on tool simplicity</strong></p>
<p><strong>Plato:</strong> Moreover, dear Homer, I must muse upon the nature of tools themselves. Much like the harmony of a well-orchestrated melody, a toolkit&rsquo;s effectiveness lies in its simplicity and single-mindedness. It is not a question of having a tool that does everything, but rather a collection of tools, each designed with a singular purpose, weaving together in harmony to accomplish grander feats.</p>
<p><strong>Homer shares his simple wisdom</strong></p>
<p><strong>Homer:</strong> You know, Plato, simplicity is like the beauty of a perfectly glazed donut. It&rsquo;s easy to understand, and it hits the spot every time. I might not have a ton of tools, but the one I&rsquo;ve got is as simple and satisfying as a classic D&rsquo;oh!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
